# **Eric Kirberger**

102 Crest Court
Milford, PA 18337
908 229 0170
erickirberger@gmail.com
https://linkedin.com/in/eric-kirberger/

## **Professional Summary**

I am a Web Developer and recent graduate of the Rutgers University Full-Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp. I excel at front-end development using technologies like React.js, node.js, and more.

I am transitioning from a 15+ year career as a teacher and head fencing instructor. As a result, I am a quick-learner and I have valuable communication skills.

### **Professional Experience**

#### **Rutgers Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp**

New Brunswick, NJ

Full-Stack Web Developer

November 2022 - February 2023

- Front-End Web Development using React, Handlebars, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and more
- Mobile-First Responsive Web Design
- Building Databases using MongoDB w. Mongoose and MySQL w. Sequelize
- Building servers using Express.js and Apollo/GraphQL
- Comfortable learning and implementing new programming languages
- Experience and comfort taking on project management roles

#### **LEW Environmental Services**

Mine Hill, NJ

Report Administrator, QA/QC Administrator, Data Entry Leader

March 2021 - June 2022

- Auditing the data files
- Analyzing 50+ page technical and legal reports for accuracy and consistency
- Staying up to date with the guidelines set out by our client and effectively communicating with my team to ensure that they have the information they need to be successful
- Dealing directly with our client, and ensuring all special requests were fulfilled
- Educating myself about other departments such as inspection, risk assessment, and remediation to have a comprehensive understanding of the business
- Training and supervising new and current employees

#### **Central Heights Fencing Club**

Stirling, NJ

Founder, Head Instructor

June 2010 – April 2020

- Coordinating a fencing schedule every year for 2 fencing teams, and adjusting as necessary
- Instructing students in the skills, strategies, and history of fencing
- Creating an environment that encourages students to participate
- Increasing students' involvement by creating and implementing innovative lesson plans

### **Long Hill Township School District**

Morris County, NJ

Substitute Teacher September 2012 – April 2020

- Teaching core subjects to children in grades 5, 6, 7, 8 with an average of 20 students per class
- Implementing teacher lesson plans, while creating ways to supplement the experience with new theories or information to spark students' interest in the material
- Adapting methods based on the fluctuating needs of the students and the evolution of the profession
- Working with a culturally and ethnically diverse population
- Developing individualized plans for students at different learning levels

Central Middle School Stirling, NJ

Fencing Coach

Nov 2010 - April 2020

- Managing equipment inventory; purchasing, maintenance, and ordering new equipment
- Working closely with the school nurse, athletic director, and other staff from various schools
- Communicating ideas clearly and effectively to both students and parents
- Improving student performance through innovative lesson plans and activities

## **Education**

Rutgers State University

B.A. in Philosophy with minor in History

New Brunswick, NJ

Pre-Service Teacher Training Program with Enhanced Clinical Experience

May 2017

**Rutgers State University** 

New Brunswick, NJ

**County College of Morris** 

Randolph, NJ May 2007

May 2014

Associate Degree

## Technologies, Certifications, and Skills

- MongoDB
- Express.js
- React.js
- Node.js
- Mongoose
- MySQL
- Sequelize
- Bootstrap
- Apollo Servers
- GraphQL
- Handlebars
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript

### Microsoft Office

State of New Jersey Teaching Certificate of Eligibility

#### References furnished upon request.